emmi@emmi.dev | denver, co | <a href="https://emmi.dev">https://emmi.dev</a>

### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My interests revolve around the cognition of preschool-aged children and their interactions with machines, specifically in the context of play. I am interested in learning and cognitive development via play and how it intersects with technology, particularly video games and mobile applications. I desire to use my professional experience as a software engineer to develop technology and research its capability to promote children's learning.

### **EDUCATION**

## The University of Chicago, Chicago, IL

June 2018

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science Bachelor of Arts with Honors - Psychology

Honors Thesis: Parents' Response Times Provide Implicit Negative Evidence for Grammar Learning

Readers: Daniel Yurovsky (advisor, primary investigator), Susan Goldin-Meadow

**GPA:** 3.5

Psychology GPA: 3.7

**Relevant coursework:** Psychological Statistics, Psychological Research Methods, Intro to Developmental Psychology, Infancy, Child Development in the Classroom, Intro to Language Development, Conceptual Development, Language for Thought and Action, Cognitive Psychology, Social Psychology, Sensation and Perception, Usable Security and Privacy, Computers for Learning, Computational Linguistics

#### **AWARDS**

# Brightspot Award, Smartsheet

2023

Nominated by colleagues for exemplifying Smartsheet's 'Earn trust' core competency. Recognized for producing high-quality software as well as excellent communication and teamwork.

### General Honors, The University of Chicago

2018

Recognition for achieving a GPA above 3.25 at the time of graduation.

# Outstanding Poster, Midwest Cognitive Science Conference

2018

Awarded by conference organizers for presentation of *Parents' response times provide implicit negative evidence for grammar learning*.

# Dean's List, The University of Chicago

2015, 2016, 2018

Awarded to the 20% of students with the highest grade point averages for that year.

# **Grace Hopper Celebration Attendance Grant, Google**

2015, 2016

Full financial support awarded to promising young women pursuing computer science to attend the Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing, a computer science research and career conference.

### Dean's Scholar, The University of Chicago

2014

\$5,000 earmarked for summer internship or research awarded as a merit scholarship upon admission.

### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

### Communication and Learning Lab (Callab), The University of Chicago

Primary Investigator: Daniel Yurovsky *Undergraduate Honors Thesis Researcher* 

December 2016 - June 2018

- + Authored Parents' Response Times Provide Implicit Negative Evidence for Grammar Learning which was approved by Daniel Yurovsky and Susan Goldin-Meadow to earn an honors distinction in the Psychology department
- + Performed computational analyses on 3 large natural language corpora using Python and R to demonstrate the existence of a novel form of negative evidence that children may use to learn English grammar
- + Designed and implemented an online self-paced reading experiment which demonstrated a processing delay when adult readers are presented with over-regularized child utterances
- + Participated in lab meetings, discussing research and providing feedback to fellow lab members

### Infant Learning and Development Laboratory, The University of Chicago

Primary Investigator: Amanda Woodward Undergraduate Research Assistant

October 2015 - October 2016

- + Coded qualitative behavioral and EEG data to support Courtney Filippi's research on infants' sensorimotor cortex activity and its correlation with their ability to shape their hands to manipulate objects
- + Participated in lab meetings, discussing relevant research and lab members' work
- + Recruited, scheduled, and escorted families to participate in research

### POSTER PRESENTATIONS

Russo, E. & Yurovsky, D. (2018, May). *Parents' response times provide implicit negative evidence for grammar learning.* Midwestern Cognitive Science Conference. Bloomington, IN.

Russo, E. & Yurovsky, D. (2018, April). *Parents' response times provide implicit negative evidence for grammar learning*. Chicago Area Undergraduate Research Symposium. Chicago, IL.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Brandfolder by Smartsheet, Denver, CO

Senior Software Engineer I Full Stack Software Developer (Software Engineer II) April 2021 - Present November 2019 - April 2021

- + Awarded <u>Smartsheet's 2023 Q1 Brightspot award</u> for the 'Earn trust' core competency in recognition of excellent software engineering, communication, and teamwork
- + Organized work, reviewed and contributed code to lead teams of 2-7 software engineers to build and update many features core to Brandfolder's offerings
- + Collaborated closely with Product and Customer Experience team members to resolve customer issues weekly
- + Mentored junior developers and supported coworkers in areas of passions like TypeScript, localization, testing, and accessibility best practices

### Microsoft, Redmond, WA

Software Engineer I

August 2018 - November 2019

- + Wrote and reviewed code to develop features for Microsoft's Azure DevOps product
- + Led feature development by identifying work to be done, collaborating with stakeholders, organizing team members, and communicating progress
- + Managed urgent customer support cases and organized team priorities and processes during on-call engineer rotations (~2 weeks every 6 weeks)

### Square, San Francisco, CA

Software Engineer Intern - Developer Platform

June - September 2017

- + Wrote and deployed industry-standard code working as a temporary member of a fast-paced team
- + Implemented an interactive widget as a tool for Square's developer' documentation website using Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, HTML, Sass, and Square's e-commerce Rails SDK

### Google, Seattle, WA

Engineering Practicum Intern - Cloud Marketplace

June - September 2016

- + Implemented a step-by-step tool that guided client partners to control the configuration options available to end customers deploying solutions offered by clients
- + Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and AngularJS to build the front-end structure of the configuration editor according to pre-defined designs as well as implement dynamic use of back-end data about the solution configuration

### Google, Mountain View, CA

Engineering Practicum Intern - Knowledge Panel UI

June - September 2015

- + Enhanced code that displays Google search result fact cards to support subscripts and superscripts across multiple platforms
- + Implemented a Java handler to identify and transform electron shell configurations and chemical formulas to render the appropriate subscript/superscript information

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

## **Programming Languages + Frameworks**

Proficient in: TypeScript/JavaScript, React, HTML + SCSS, Ruby on Rails, SQL

Exposure to: ¡Query, AngularJS, C, Python, Java, R, SML, XML

### Platforms + Tools

Proficient in: Git, Unix (Bash scripting), Yarn/NPM, Google Cloud Build, PostgreSQL, Smartsheet

**Exposure to:** Docker, Datadog, Mode, BigQuery, Firestore, Amazon Mechanical Turk, RStudio, PowerBl, Google Cloud Run, Google AppEngine, Firebase